chamberlain.com 2019-12-08

# Chamberlain

## **PRIVACY POLICY**

[European Economic Area Resident Privacy Policy – English (UK)](https://embed.widencdn.net/pdf/plus/cgi/m0duyvfxt6/EEA-Privacy-Policy-Final-English-UK.pdf?u=qybkog&use=zz6ja)

[United States and Other Non-Eurpoean Countries – English (US) ](https://embed.widencdn.net/pdf/plus/cgi/070f7xbci8/EEA-Privacy-Policy-Final--English-US.pdf?u=qybkog&use=zz6ja)

[United States and Other Non-Eurpoean Countries – Prior version (English)](https://embed.widencdn.net/pdf/plus/cgi/xi88vlb6ce/North-America-Privacy-Policy--Prior-version-English.pdf?u=qybkog&use=zz6ja)

### **Effective Date: May 18, 2018**

Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy describes the types of information The Chamberlain Group, Inc. and its wholly and majority-owned entities (“CGI”) collects from and about you when you visit  [www.chamberlain.com](https://www.chamberlain.com/), [www.liftmaster.com](https://www.liftmaster.com/), [www.chamberlaingroup.com](http://www.chamberlaingroup.com/), [https://dealer.liftmaster.com](https://dealer.liftmaster.com/), [https://www.myq.com](https://www.myq.com/) or any other of our websites where this policy is posted (each a “Site”), use our products, including, without limitation, IPAC, CapXL, LiftMaster Cloud Services, and HomeBridge, use our mobile applications (each an “App”), including, without limitation, MyQ®, or otherwise interact with us or request services from us as described further in this Privacy Policy. The Sites, Apps, and other interactions are collectively the “Services.” This Privacy Policy also explains how CGI and its affiliated entities may use and disclose such information, as well as your ability to control certain uses of your personal information.

The following policy applies to anyone who is not a resident of the European Economic Area (“EEA”).

By using any of our Services, you agree to the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not, please do not use the Services.

## INFORMATION COLLECTION

#### Information You Provide

We collect information from you when you choose to share it with us. This may include when you use our Services, search for a retailer or dealer, create an online account with us, register a product with us, provide information to one of our sales coordinators, speak with one of our representatives by phone, sign up for newsletters or our email list, participate in a survey or promotion, request information from us, or otherwise contact us.The information we collect from you may include, but is not limited to:

  * Contact information, including your name, address, email address, telephone, or mobile number;

  * Employer-related information, such as your title and the company’s name, address, and phone number;

  * Credit or debit card number or other financial information;

  * CGI account number;

  * Geolocation of any computer, mobile device, or other electronic device used to access a Site, App or product;

  * Information regarding the products or equipment purchased;

  * Information regarding your usage of, and performance of, our products, equipment and Apps; and

  * Charges you incur and other information relating to your transactions.

#### Information Collected from Third Parties or Other Sources

We may obtain personal or other information about you from third parties or other sources, and combine this information with the information we collect from and about you through the Services. Such information may include, but is not limited to:

  * Information, including geolocation information, collected through one of our mobile applications;

  * Information obtained through communications that you make through a third party, such as through our network of independent retailers and/or dealers;

  * Information obtained through transactions you complete with us or our retailers, including charges you incur;

  * Information about your credit history or other publicly available information about you from consumer reporting agencies; and

  * Any other information obtained through companies that have business relationships with us, such as our licensees, affiliates, and business partners.

We may also obtain information about you from other online sources, including when you connect with CGI through its official corporate pages on third party social networks (such as Facebook) or the “apps” on those pages. This information may include, but is not limited to, name, user name, demographic information, updated address or contact information, interests, and publicly-observed data, such as from social media and online activity. We may combine this information with the information we collect from and about you through the Services.

#### Information Automatically Collected

We may use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, JavaScript, or other technologies to collect certain information about visitors to any of our Sites or Apps and interactions with our emails and online or mobile advertisements, and may use such information to allow CGI to keep track of analytics and certain statistical information which enables us to improve our Sites and Apps and provide you with more relevant content and advertising on our Sites, Apps, or other websites or mobile applications.

For example, we may automatically collect certain information from you, including but not limited to your browser type, device type, operating system, software version, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, geolocation, phone model, phone operating system, and the domain name from which you accessed the Services. We also may collect information about your use of a Site or App, including the date and time you visit the Site or App, the areas or pages of the Site or App that you visit, the amount of time you spend viewing or using the Site or App, the number of times you return to the Site or App, other click-stream or site usage data, emails that you open, forward or click-through to our Site or App, and other sites that you may visit.

We may also use third party cookies and other technologies to support our Services, provide services on our behalf, facilitate business transactions on our behalf, or provide relevant advertising to you. Some of these third parties may use technology such as cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, log files, or Flash cookies on our Sites or Apps, which may send some of the above-referenced information to those third parties.

#### Tracking Options and California Do Not Track Disclosures

Certain parts of our Sites and Apps require cookies. You are free to set your browser or operating system settings to limit certain tracking or to decline cookies, but by doing so you may not be able to use certain features on the applicable Site or App, or take full advantage of all of our offerings. Please refer to your Web browser’s or operating system’s website or “Help” section for more information on how to delete and/or disable your browser or operating system from receiving cookies or controlling your tracking preferences.

Our system may not respond to Do Not Track requests or headers from some or all browsers. To learn more about the use of cookies or other technologies to deliver more relevant advertising and to know your choices about not having this information used by certain service providers, please visit <http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/> and [ https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245). On your mobile device, you may also adjust your privacy and advertising settings to control whether you want to receive more relevant advertising.

Certain parts of our Sites and/or Apps may also include advertisements from third parties. You can opt-out of being targeted by certain third-party ad-servers and CGI served ads online using the National Advertising Initiative’s opt-out tool, the About Ads opt-out tool, or on TRUSTe’s site.

This Privacy Policy does not cover the collection methods or use of the information collected by Third-Party Ad-Servers, and CGI is not responsible for cookies or other tracking technology in third-party ads. We encourage you to review the privacy policies or statements of these third-party advertising companies to learn more about their use of cookies and other technologies. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by third-party advertisers, please visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org](https://www.networkadvertising.org/) and [http://www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/)

#### Combination of Information

We may combine the information we receive from and about you, including information you provide to us and information we automatically collect through our Sites, Apps and other services, as well as information collected from other online sources or from third party sources to help us tailor our communications to you and to improve our Services.

#### INFORMATION USE

CGI may use the information we collect from and about you for any of the following purposes:

  * To validate, confirm, verify, and track your account, products or services (including to process payment card transactions, or to contact you about your account, products or services);

  * To enhance your online experience, including as a way to recognize you and welcome you to a Site or App, make the account usage and purchasing process faster and smoother and provide you with customized Site or App content, targeted offers, and advertising on Sites, Apps (including geo-targeted advertising), or via email, telephone, text message, or by mail;

  * To recognize your online activities over time and across different websites and devices;

  * To contact you with information, newsletters, promotional materials and contests from CGI or on behalf of our business partners, licensees, and affiliates;

  * We may also share user information with our co-sponsors, business partners and service providers to offer products or services which we believe may be valuable or useful to our visitors. They may use a pixel tag or other similar technology to collect anonymous information about your visits to Sites, and they may use that information to target advertisements for our products and Services.

  * To use your data in an aggregated non-specific format for analytical and demographic purposes;

  * To review the usage and operations of our Sites, Apps and other Services, and improve our content, products, and services;

  * To protect the security or integrity of the Sites, Apps, and our business, such as by protecting against and preventing fraud, unauthorized transactions, claims and other liabilities, and managing risk exposure, including by identifying potential hackers and other unauthorized users; and

  * As otherwise described to you at the point of data collection.

Additionally, if you use any of the Sites or Apps to connect with third party services you authorize us to use information from and about you, on your behalf, to interact with these third party services based on your requests.

#### INFORMATION SHARING

CGI may disclose the personal information we collect from and about you in the following ways:

  * With our affiliated companies, retailers and dealers, including subsidiaries of such companies;

  * With our third party service providers that provide business, professional or technical support functions for us;

  * With our agents, licensees, and other companies that assist us in providing a product or service to you, including, but not limited to, making your purchase and installation; providing you with customer assistance; processing and/or confirming your transactions; providing you with the services you requested; assessing creditworthiness; billing and collecting any amounts owed in connection with your account or products or services purchased; or recovering any monies due, such as through debt collection agencies;

  * With our select licensees, affiliates, retailers and business partners that we believe may have offers of interest to you, including for their own marketing purposes;

  * We may also engage one or more third-party service providers to serve online advertisements on our behalf.

  * As necessary if we believe that there has been a violation of our Terms of Use or of our rights or the rights of any third party;

  * To respond to judicial process or provide information to law enforcement or regulatory agencies or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety, as permitted by law, or otherwise as required by law; and

  * As otherwise described to you at the point of collection.

CGI may also share aggregate or anonymous non-personal information with third parties for their marketing or analytics uses.

Also, CGI may sell or purchase assets during the normal course of our business. If another entity acquires us or any of our assets, information we have collected about you may be transferred to such entity. In addition, if any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding is brought by or against us, such information may be considered an asset of ours and may be sold or transferred to third parties. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to require that the transferee use personal information provided through the Services in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.

#### YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

If you are a California resident, you may request information about our disclosure of personal information to third parties or affiliated companies for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at:

The Chamberlain Group, Inc.  
Attn: Data Privacy Department  
300 Windsor Drive,  
Oak Brook, IL 60523  
(630) 279-3600  
Email: [privacy@chamberlain.com ](mailto:privacy@chamberlain.com?subject=Attn%3A%20Data%20Privacy%20Department)

You must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the subject field. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information. 

Non-affiliated third parties are independent from CGI and if you wish to receive information about your disclosure choices or stop communications from such third parties, you will need to contact those non-affiliated third parties directly.

#### LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES

The Sites, Apps, and email messages from us may contain links to third-party websites, which may have privacy policies that differ from our own. You should be aware that the collection, retention and use of any data you provide on these websites will be governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the website and not by this policy. We are not responsible for the practices of such websites.

#### PUBLIC FORUMS

Any information you may disclose on our Sites or Apps, in blogs, on message boards, in chat rooms, or on other public areas on a Site, App, or other third-party website that the Site or App may link to, becomes public information. Please exercise caution when disclosing personal information in these public areas. We reserve the right to remove any posting or content in a posting at our sole discretion.

#### CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

Protecting children’s privacy is important to us. We do not direct our Sites or Apps to, nor do we knowingly collect any personal information from, children under the age of thirteen. If we learn that a child under the age of thirteen has provided personally identifiable information to a Site or App, we will use reasonable efforts to remove such information from the files of such Site or App.

#### DATA SECURITY

We have taken certain physical, administrative, and technical steps to safeguard the information we collect from and about our customers and Site and App visitors. While we make every reasonable effort to help ensure the integrity and security of our network and systems, we cannot guarantee our security measures.

#### DATA STORAGE

Your personal information may be stored on servers in the United States and is subject to the laws of the United States, where the data protection and other laws may differ from those of other countries. Your personal information may be disclosed in response to inquiries or requests from government authorities or to respond to judicial process in the countries in which we operate.

#### YOUR OPTIONS AND ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We provide our customers with the opportunity to opt-out of having their information used for purposes not directly related to purchase, processing, registration or ongoing services. To “opt out” of receiving future e-mail marketing messages from CGI, you can click on the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of an e-mail marketing message or contact us as provided below under “Contact Us”. Please allow 10 business days for your request to take effect.

To access, review, or update your information stored by CGI, you may visit the Account Profile page on the Sites or the Apps, where you can view, update, or change your personal information and update your member profile, password, and associated information.

If you have any additional questions concerning access to or updating your personal information, please contact us at the information provided in the “Contact Us” section below.

#### CONTACT US

We hope this policy answers your questions about our collection, use and disclosure of your personal data. If you have additional questions about this Privacy Policy or the practices described herein, you may contact us at 630-279-3600 or write to us at the following address:

The Chamberlain Group, Inc.  
Attn: Data Privacy Department  
300 Windsor Drive,  
Oak Brook, IL 60523  
(630) 279-3600  
Email: [privacy@chamberlain.com ](mailto:privacy@chamberlain.com?subject=Attn%3A%20Data%20Privacy%20Department)

#### USER’S ACCEPTANCE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY

By using the Services, you signify your acceptance to the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Services.

#### REVISIONS TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

CGI reserves the right, at its sole discretion, to change, modify, add, remove, or otherwise revise portions of this Privacy Policy at any time. If we do, we will make you aware of the change(s) on the Site or App by including a link to the previous version of the Privacy Policy. Your continued use of the Site or App following the posting of changes to these terms means you accept these changes. If we change this Privacy Policy in a material way, we will provide appropriate notice to you.
